<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>20 Champions on Golden Thread Productions</title>
    <link>/tags/20-champions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 20 Champions on Golden Thread Productions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 17:15:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/20-champions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Mona Mansour</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-mona-mansour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 17:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-mona-mansour/</guid>
      <description>Award-winning playwright Mona Mansour has been a part of the Golden Thread family since 2009. Golden Thread has produced the West Coast premiere of her Urge For Going as well as two short plays she co-authored with Tala Manassah. And Mona is the current Middle East America Award winner, and we’re looking forward to continuing our work on her new commissioned play. What was your first experience with Golden Thread and when?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Linda Chang and Emin Maltepe</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-linda-emin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 17:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-linda-emin/</guid>
      <description>Linda Chang and Emin Maltepe are longtime champions of youth and family programming at Golden Thread. Emin has served on the Board of Trustees for two terms and both, along with their daughter Tulin continue to be among our staunchest supporters. We are excited to recognize them as one of our 20 champions. What was your first experience with Golden Thread and when? Tulin’s first experience with Golden Thread was at a Fairytale Players performance of The Girl Who Lost Her Smile at a library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Hafiz Karmali</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-hafiz-karmali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 17:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-hafiz-karmali/</guid>
      <description>Award-winning director Hafiz Karmali has directed numerous productions for Golden Thread, including Island of Animals, Rumi x 7 = Tales from the Masnavi, Night Over Erzinga, and plays for ReOrient Festivals. His visual and physical approach and his deep knowledge of Islamic styles and myths have made him an audience favorite with Golden Thread regulars. What was your first experience with Golden Thread and when? My relationship with Golden Thread Productions and the company’s Founding Artistic Director, Torange Yeghiazarian, goes back ten years!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Termeh Yeghiazarian</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-termeh-yeghiazarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 23:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-termeh-yeghiazarian/</guid>
      <description>Termeh Yeghiazarian, a visual artist, is one of the co-founders of Golden Thread. She was an essential part of the discussions that led to Golden Thread’s inclusive and groundbreaking vision of Middle Eastern-American theatre. She is also Torange Yeghiazarian’s sister, and artistic talent and disregard to instructions must run in the Yeghiazarian family, as Termeh answered our questions with a freeform blog. We’re so very excited to include her voice in this celebration of 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Guenet Sebsibe</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-guenet-sebsibe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 19:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-guenet-sebsibe/</guid>
      <description>Guenet Sebsibe is a longtime Golden Thread audience member. Her smiling face at performances and inquisitive questions at talkbacks are always a favorite of our staff. We are thankful that audience members like Guenet are eager and willing to hear these stories, and share our work with their friends and family. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t be prouder to have Guenet as one of our 20 Champions. What was your first experience with Golden Thread and when?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Sara Razavi</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-sara-razavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 21:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-sara-razavi/</guid>
      <description>Sara Razavi was a very obvious choice to include as one of our 20 Champions. What has Sara not done for Golden Thread? She’s been on our stages (most memorably in Yussef El Guindi’s The Monologist Suffers Her Monologue), directed numerous plays for the ReOrient, served on our Board of Trustees, including as president of the board (2011-2013). We are very lucky to have her as part of the Golden Thread family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Tom Hanks&#39; Seat</title>
      <link>/posts/walid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 22:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/walid/</guid>
      <description>In Tom Hanks&amp;rsquo; Seat an interview with Walid Azad
Walid Azad is a member of the production team of The Most Dangerous Highway in the World and has been an invaluable resource to the cast and the creative team. Like many Afghans living in the Bay Area, Walid Azad left Afghanistan in the 1980’s. He had to cross the border to Pakistan illegally and on foot then wait in Pakistan for months until his brother who was already living in the Bay Area would secure a visa for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience and Hope in Afghanistan</title>
      <link>/posts/hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 21:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hope/</guid>
      <description>Resilience and Hope in Afghanistan by Torange Yeghizarian
Most people think of the Taliban or Osama Bin Laden when they hear Afghanistan mentioned. But this landlocked country of 32 million has been thriving since 2nd century AD. The beginning of modern Afghanistan can be dated to 1747, when Ahmad Khan Abdali was elected king of the Afghans in a tribal assembly in Kandahar. Because of its strategic location, Afghanistan has always been of interest to foreign powers, but its terrain is so rugged that no military campaign, dating back to Alexander the Great and the Soviet Russians has succeeded in fully subduing its population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Jim Lucas</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-jim-lucas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 23:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-jim-lucas/</guid>
      <description>Jim Lucas, a board member from 2003-2008, is the founder of Lucavia Consulting focused on helping small businesses grow and become sustainable, and his advice and insight has been a real help to Golden Thread’s steady growth over the last decade. He and his wife Josephine are always at the heart of every Golden Thread celebration, and he is quite the handy man, having helped load in and strike many a complicated set at our theatres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capturing the Feeling of Afghanistan</title>
      <link>/posts/highway-costumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 22:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/highway-costumes/</guid>
      <description>Capturing the Feeling of Afghanistan by Courtney Flores, Costume Designer
The Most Dangerous Highway in the World is inspired by a New York Times article about the real-life &amp;ldquo;Pepsi Bottle boys&amp;rdquo; of Afghanistan. Costume designer Courtney Flores tells us about her creative process and her immersion in the Afghan culture with the help of our Afghan consultant Humaira Ghilzai, and shares her beautiful costume sketches for the world premiere production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Champions: Yussef El Guindi</title>
      <link>/posts/20-champions-yussef/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 23:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20-champions-yussef/</guid>
      <description>Award-winning Egyptian-American playwright Yussef El Guindi, whose Our Enemies: Lively Scenes of Love and Combat is coming up in the fall, holds the honor of being the most produced playwright at Golden Thread. His previous premieres with the company include Language Rooms, Jihad Jones and the Kalashnikov Babes, Back of the Throat, Scenic Routes, and many shorts in ReOrient Festivals. Golden Thread performed El Guindi’s _Karima’s City_ at the Cairo International Festival for Experimental Theatre in 2004.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>