<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lmda on Golden Thread Productions</title>
    <link>/tags/lmda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lmda on Golden Thread Productions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 04:53:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/lmda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women’s Voices Naturally Rise to the Top at Golden Thread</title>
      <link>/posts/womens-voices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 04:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/womens-voices/</guid>
      <description>by Maddie Gaw, ReOrient Publications Dramaturg
_As a team member of the first-time partnership between Golden Thread and Literary Managers and Dramaturgs of the Americas, Publications Dramaturg Maddie Gaw interviews playwrights Betty Shamieh (Make No Mistake), E.H. Benedict (War on Terror), and Torange Yeghiazarian (Thanksgiving at Khodabakhshian’s) to discuss their writing careers as women and in the Bay Area, and experiences with Golden Thread._
ABOUT MADDIE GAW Maddie Gaw is a dramaturg, writer, producer, and arts administrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReOrient Profile: Playwright and Dramaturg Tackle Manar a Third Time</title>
      <link>/posts/manar-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 23:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/manar-profile/</guid>
      <description>ReOrient Profile: Playwright and Dramaturg Tackle Manar a Third Time Dramaturg Anna Woodruff in Conversation with Playwright Melis Aker
_As a team member of the first-time partnership between Golden Thread and Literary Managers and Dramaturgs of the Americas, ReOrient Dramaturg Anna Woodruff speaks with her longtime collaborator and Playwright Melis Aker about their working relationship, the evolution of Manar, and their experience with Golden Thread._
![Anna Woodruff](/img/archive/2017/12/Woodruff-Anna.jpg) **ABOUT ANNA WOODRUFF** Anna Woodruff is a dramaturg based in New York City who focuses on new play development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being in the Room: Transatlantic Collaborations in ReOrient 2017</title>
      <link>/posts/being-in-the-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 21:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/being-in-the-room/</guid>
      <description>BEING IN THE ROOM: Transatlantic Collaborations in ReOrient 2017 by Emily DeDakis, ReOrient Publications Dramaturg
_As a team member of the first-time partnership between Golden Thread and Literary Managers and Dramaturgs of the Americas, Publications Dramaturg Emily DeDakis interviews ReOrient playwrights Sevan K. Greene (A is for Ali) and Hannah Khalil (The Rehearsal) to discuss their plays, playwriting careers in the U.K., and past experiences with Golden Thread._
![Emily DeDakis](/img/archive/2017/11/Emily-DeDakis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Ready to ReOrient?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-you-ready-to-reorient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 20:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/are-you-ready-to-reorient/</guid>
      <description>Are You Ready to ReOrient? Festival Overview by Vidhu Singh, ReOrient Publications Dramaturg
As a team member of the first-time partnership between Golden Thread and Literary Managers and Dramaturgs of the Americas, Publications Dramaturg Vidhu Singh takes you behind-the scenes of ReOrient and highlights the importance of Golden Thread in the American theatre.
![Vidhu Singh](/img/archive/2017/11/headshot-vidhu-singh.jpg) **ABOUT VIDHU SINGH** BRAVA Artist-in- Residence Vidhu Singh is a theatre director, scholar, and dramaturg who is a key player in the South Asian Theater Arts Movement in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>