<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isfahanblues on Golden Thread Productions</title>
    <link>/tags/isfahanblues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Isfahanblues on Golden Thread Productions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 23:01:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/isfahanblues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Isfahan Blues Closes with a Bang!</title>
      <link>/posts/isfahan-blues-closes-with-a-bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 23:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/isfahan-blues-closes-with-a-bang/</guid>
      <description>Isfahan Blues Closes with a Bang! _ Audience numbers reach record breaking highs _ We are thrilled to announce that_ Isfahan Blues_ reached a record-breaking high in audience numbers this May. With over 2,000 tickets sold, there was hardly an empty-seat in the entire theater!
We are so proud to have shared this production with so many, and whether this was your first time seeing a Golden Thread production or you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned Golden Thread audience member, we hope you&amp;rsquo;ll join us this September for the **ReOrient 2015 Festival of Short Plays &amp;amp; Forum!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Iranian Film Star is Born!</title>
      <link>/posts/an_iranian_film_star_is_born/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 23:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/an_iranian_film_star_is_born/</guid>
      <description>An Iranian Film Star is Born! by Nakissa Etemad, Isfahan Blues Dramaturg Poster for the film Tomorrow is Bright, co-starring Vigen (Iran’s King of Pop &amp;amp; Sultan of Jazz), Fardin (her leading man), and popular singer Delkash. Vida’s character dons Western looks to re-attract her cheating husband.
Eager to establish Iran as a political leader and economic powerhouse, the Shah of Iran Mohammad Reza Pahlavi (ruler from 1941-1979) led the nation towards industrialization and social reform modeled after Western democracies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America&#39;s Goodwill Ambassador</title>
      <link>/posts/americasgoodwillambassador/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 22:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/americasgoodwillambassador/</guid>
      <description>America&amp;rsquo;s Goodwill Ambassador by Nakissa Etemad, Isfahan Blues Dramaturg 
Album Cover of Duke Ellington’s The Far East Suite, RCA Victor, 1967
The Civil Rights Movement reached its height in 1963 when Martin Luther King, Jr. led 250,000 at the March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom on August 28. On September 15, the 16th Street Baptist Church in Birmingham—used as a meeting place by Civil Rights leaders—was bombed by reported members of the Ku Klux Klan, resulting in the death of four black girls aged 11 to 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isfahan Blues Brings Two Communities Together</title>
      <link>/posts/isfahan-blues-brings-two-communities-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 20:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/isfahan-blues-brings-two-communities-together/</guid>
      <description>NEW VIDEO: Isfahan Blues Brings Two Communities Together 
&amp;ldquo;Collaboration is huge,&amp;rdquo; insists L. Peter Callender, Artistic Director of African-American Shakespeare Company,&amp;ldquo;and we&amp;rsquo;re hoping that our audiences meet each other, tell stories about their experiences&amp;hellip;and that friendships are forged in the audiences, as well as on stage!&amp;rdquo;
Delve deeper into the collaborative process behind Isfahan Blues, a rare and important partnership between two companies of color, in this new video interview!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcus Shelby Music</title>
      <link>/posts/marcus_shelby_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 21:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/marcus_shelby_music/</guid>
      <description>Shelby Brings a Swinging Beat to Isfahan Blues Are you a Jazz lover like us? Then you have yet another reason to love Isfahan Blues, inspired by the Duke Ellington Orchestra&amp;rsquo;s 1963 tour of Iran. Bay Area Jazz great Marcus Shelby is composing music for the world premiere and ** 7x7 Magazine is as excited as we are about Shelby&amp;rsquo;s contribution. **</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>