<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reorient2015 on Golden Thread Productions</title>
    <link>/tags/reorient2015/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reorient2015 on Golden Thread Productions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 22:52:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/reorient2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Heartfelt ReOrient Thank You</title>
      <link>/posts/10166/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 22:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10166/</guid>
      <description>A Heartfelt ReOrient Thank You from the Golden Thread staff
We want to thank our Golden Thread family—artists, supporters, and volunteers—for making this year&amp;rsquo;s ReOrient so special. It really takes a village. TELL US WHAT YOU THINK! Did you attend one of our ReOrient events? Please take a moment to fill out our online survey. Your opinion is very important to us!
WATCH THE CONVERSATIONS ONLINE! Did you miss the ReOrient Forum?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-calibration and Re-orientation</title>
      <link>/posts/10152/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 18:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10152/</guid>
      <description>Re-calibration and Re-orientation by Kamee Abrahamian Co-Chair, &amp;ldquo;Orientations&amp;rdquo; panel on Saturday, October 3, at 5pm in ReOrient Forum 2015
When we moved into a new apartment, I was afraid to let the cat out. “WHAT IF HE GOES OUTSIDE BUT FEELS SAD AND REGRETS IT THEN CAN’T FIND HIS WAY HOME?” I cried to the internet. Apparently, it takes a cat three months to recalibrate their compass and sense of space, then they should be able to find their way back instinctually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Folk Song Recital with Saousan Jarjour</title>
      <link>/posts/10133/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 21:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10133/</guid>
      <description>Arabic Folk Song Recital with Saousan Jarjour ** Saturday, October 3, at 2pm at Z Space (450 Florida Street, San Francisco) Tickets are available here
**
At this one day recital, award–winning Syrian-American soprano Saousan Jarjour will present an exciting program of modern and jazzy interpretations of her favorite Arabic folk songs. Accompanied by the talented Zetune Ensemble, Jarjour will re-imagine classics like Ziad Rahbani&amp;rsquo;s “Sabah Wu Masa,” Fairouz’s “Aa Hadeer al Bosta,” and “Hal Asmar Ellon” amongst many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Past and Present with Music</title>
      <link>/posts/10079/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 22:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10079/</guid>
      <description>Bridging the Past and Present with Music by Saousan Jarjour Saousan is featured in Arab Folk Song Recital on Saturday, October 3, at 2pm.
Singing folk songs in Syria was a bridge that connected the past with the present, the young with the old, and all were welcomed to join in the circle and sing along. The same songs were always sung, played in the car, bus, or circle of chairs out in the farm or village under the starry sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReOrient 2015 Photos Are Here!</title>
      <link>/posts/10030/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 19:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/10030/</guid>
      <description>ReOrient 2015 Photos Are Here! Photographer David Allen visited the final dress rehearsals of ReOrient 2015 and took some beautiful photos for the nine featured plays. Check out the shots here. If you are a member of the press, and need hi-res versions of these photos, please email Evren Odcikin at evren@goldenthread.org.
Picking Up the Scent by Yussef El Guindi, directed by Evren Odcikin Syrian poet Nisrin (Nora el Samahy) remembers her husband Hisham (Damien Seperi) in Yussef El Guindi&amp;rsquo;s Picking Up the Scent, directed by Evren Odcikin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning a New Conversation About Iran</title>
      <link>/posts/9990/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 22:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/9990/</guid>
      <description>Beginning a New Conversation About Iran by Sara Razavi, Director
Members of my family, like many Iranians, emigrated from Iran in waves. Some of our family left to study abroad before the 1979 Islamic Revolution, and never returned. Some fled after the Islamic Revolution because of persecution. And some, like my immediate family, left because of “the War.” And one of the two plays I’m directing this year, Songs of Our Childhood by Nahal Navidar, is set in 1980 in an Iranian triage on the frontlines of the Iran-Iraq War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Resist With Theatre</title>
      <link>/posts/9981/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 09:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/9981/</guid>
      <description>How to Resist With Theatre by Nora el Samahy, Actor
In Yussef El Guindi’s play, Picking up the Scent, the character Hisham alludes to resisting against ‘the tyrants’ through doing what he loves, archaeology, while his wife Nisrin does so through poetry. Needless to say, many of us from the Middle East have been at a loss of how to resist over the last five years, whether we’re there or here: far away with an ache of how to connect, react, feel, and take action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Doesn&#39;t Love a Good Puzzle?</title>
      <link>/posts/9970/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 18:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/9970/</guid>
      <description>Who Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Love a Good Puzzle? by Wesley Apfel, Production Stage Manager
As an audience member, I enjoy my share of thought-provoking theatre. And as a theatre professional, I love a good puzzle to figure out. This is my second year as the Production Stage Manager of ReOrient, and while I’ve done some festivals before, nothing could quite prepare me for the unique challenges of rehearsing so many short plays simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Risk of Being a &#34;Niche&#34; Artist</title>
      <link>/posts/9937/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/9937/</guid>
      <description>The Risk of Being a &amp;ldquo;Niche&amp;rdquo; Artist by Nahal Navidar, Playwright
A visceral energy of excitement is palpable as I walk into the rehearsal space for Golden Thread’s ReOrient meet and greet. Actors, directors, playwrights, designers, and production staff chat full of inspired ideas for the weeks to come. In many ways, this spirited encounter is not unlike the initial production meetings that take place in so many rehearsal spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Middle East Personal</title>
      <link>/posts/9871/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 17:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/9871/</guid>
      <description>Making the Middle East Personal by Lawrence Radecker, Actor
ReOrient is a joy for me. I get to work with some of the most talented artists in the Bay Area, plus I get to study a different culture with each show. I participated in my first Reorient in 2003, which was an all-encompassing learning experience. I played an Israeli dad in one piece and a white racist security guard in another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Beyond My Own Culture</title>
      <link>/posts/9811/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 04:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/9811/</guid>
      <description>Writing Beyond My Own Culture by Emma Goldman-Sherman, Playwright
My play, Counting in Sha’ab, about a community in Iraq, mostly wrote itself before I knew anything about Iraq. I adapted it from an article in the New York Times that immediately struck me and created an emotional response large enough to send me inside that world. I could see the canned goods on the shelves of the grocery store where the play is set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost No More!</title>
      <link>/posts/9678/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 21:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/9678/</guid>
      <description>Ghost No More! by Playwright Yussef El Guindi
ReOrient is a big bundle of drama, comedy, lyricism, surreal somersaults into strange landscapes, or realistic lunges into sensitive topics (among other things). A ReOrient stage is a stage stuffed with unique viewpoints and unconventional ideas that come from a much misunderstood, and frequently maligned, part of the world. I’ve always been a tad gobsmacked that, given the Middle East’s prominence in world affairs, larger theaters, for the most part, stay away from plays that want to probe the culture and politics of that region.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>