<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productions on Golden Thread Productions</title>
    <link>/productions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productions on Golden Thread Productions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 20:06:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/productions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Periphery</title>
      <link>/productions/on-the-periphery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 20:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/on-the-periphery/</guid>
      <description>Set in Istanbul and Paris, Ecer’s new play focuses on the rarely told stories of migrants in Istanbul’s urban slums. Farmers Dilsha and Bilo leave their home in the countryside to make a life in the big city. Young lovers Azad and Tamar appeal to superstar Sultane’s reality TV show to realize their dream of a life in France. Roma woman, Kibele, finds home in a shack she has made with her own hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jogging</title>
      <link>/productions/jogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 20:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/jogging/</guid>
      <description>Her body is stimulated through exercise with two hormones, dopamine and adrenaline, alternating between destruction and construction. In Medea-like fashion, this cycle within Hajj Ali — woman, wife and mother — echoes that of her city, one that destroys to build and builds to destroy.
Acclaimed Lebanese writer and performer, Hajj Ali brings her one-woman show to the Bay Area following her celebrated performances at the Kennedy Center and the Guthrie Theater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Language of Wild Berries</title>
      <link>/productions/the-language-of-wild-berries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 22:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/the-language-of-wild-berries/</guid>
      <description>Donya and Davood celebrate their wedding anniversary by traveling to the same sea side town where they spent their honeymoon. But on this trip, their 10th anniversary, a mysterious young man is following them. Who is he? What does he want? Trying to solve the mystery of the young man throws Donya and Davood into a time warp recalling their past nine anniversary trips. They remember what they have forgotten. But will that be enough to save their marriage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do the Women Say? 2020</title>
      <link>/productions/what-do-the-women-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 23:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/what-do-the-women-say/</guid>
      <description>This year’s program showcases the work of leading Middle Eastern women artists and examines the ways in which artists express political agency in cultural production. With a lineup of acclaimed artists surveying their diverse Middle Eastern cultures, the singular evening celebrates women who reject narrowly defined stereotypes to take ownership of their creative processes and carve out their own innovative identities.
The event includes an excerpt from animated series Marvel Rising featuring Kathreen Khavari as the voice of Ms Marvel, the first Muslim super hero and.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Threads Reading Series 2020</title>
      <link>/productions/new-threads-reading-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 19:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/new-threads-reading-series/</guid>
      <description>Since its launch in 2011, many New Threads plays and playwrights have continued on to receive mainstage productions. The readings are accompanied by talkbacks with the artists and experts that comment on the themes of the play.
We invite you to join the creative process of a new play and discover brilliant gems never before seen in the Bay Area. We invite you to laugh, cry, and think alongside these beautiful stories from and about the Middle East.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReOrient 2019</title>
      <link>/productions/reorient-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/reorient-2019/</guid>
      <description>This year’s ReOrient Festival marks our second collaboration with the Literary Managers and Dramaturgs of the Americas (LMDA). The partnership brings together two organizations that value challenging cultural preconceptions through provocative programming and dialogue. Curated by LMDA’s Regional VP Metro Bay Area and Festival Lead Dramaturg Nakissa Etemad, LMDA is providing a team of Dramaturgs to aid the playwrights in script development, provide contextual information, and write feature articles that peek behind-the-scenes of ReOrient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leila’s Quest For Flight</title>
      <link>/productions/leila/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/leila/</guid>
      <description>Golden Thread Fairytale Players offer a dynamic repertoire of performances for young audiences, with plays based on traditions and folklore from across the Middle East.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Behalf of All Muslims: A Comedy Special</title>
      <link>/productions/obam-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/obam-2019/</guid>
      <description>“Zahra’s voice is an asset in the polarizing and often violent political turmoil we live in as Americans today.” —W. Kamau Bell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scenes From 71* Years</title>
      <link>/productions/scenes-from-71-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/scenes-from-71-years/</guid>
      <description>Reviews ★★★★★ &amp;#8220;Exceptional&amp;#8230; wickedly funny and heartbreaking&amp;#8221; —The Stage
★★★★ &amp;#8220;A deeply compassionate play&amp;#8230; a powerful yet tender collection of everyday vignettes&amp;#8221; —Time Out
&amp;#8220;This new work confirms Hannah Khalil as a dramatist of compelling potential.&amp;#8221; —Telegraph
&amp;#8220;Smart and economical, simultaneously resonant with warmth and humanity, and shot through with exquisitely dark comedy. These scenes combine into a deft, kaleidoscopic portrait of ongoing struggle, acceptance, and simple survival.&amp;#8221; —Exeunt Magazine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do the Women Say? 2019</title>
      <link>/productions/wdtws-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/wdtws-2019/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I loved the amazing stories of women whose voices are not always given a platform.&amp;#8221; —What Do the Women Say? 2018 Audience member</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Swim, We Talk, We Go to War</title>
      <link>/productions/we-talk-we-swim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 20:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/we-talk-we-swim/</guid>
      <description>This play was commissioned by Middle East America: A National New Plays Initiative, created by Golden Thread Productions (San Francisco), The Lark (New York City), and Silk Road Rising (Chicago). Mona Mansour is the third winner of the Middle East America Distinguished Playwright Award, which was previously awarded to Adriana Sevahn Nichols and Yussef El Guindi.
Reviews HIGHEST RATING! &amp;ldquo;A unifying cleanse&amp;hellip; Mansour’s disarmingly naturalistic dialogue helps make these seismic structural shifts work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love, Bombs, and Apples</title>
      <link>/productions/love-bombs-and-apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/love-bombs-and-apples/</guid>
      <description>Reviews “Directed by Rosamunde Hutt with careful attention to varied moods and nuances, Abdulrazzak’s monologues form a rich and seamless whole. Beautifully encapsulates a dilemma that’s complex, hilarious and utterly believable.” —San Francisco Examiner
“A provocative and hilarious solo show… Hassan Abdulrazzak brilliantly wrings comedy from the idiosyncratic obsessions of four very different young men as their lives intersect with the tragic state of the world around them.” —Mercury News</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do the Women Say? 2018</title>
      <link>/productions/wdtws-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/wdtws-2018/</guid>
      <description>Community Partners
The Center for Middle Eastern Studies, UC Berkeley
Global Fund For Women
Islamic Cultural Center of Northern California
The Markaz: Resource Center, Stanford University
Women’s Voices Now</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh My Sweet Land</title>
      <link>/productions/sweet-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 20:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/sweet-land/</guid>
      <description>Zuabi says of his experience of working on the play: “We met people in the harshest moments of their life, yet still they were generous, full of grace, hope, and even humor. This piece is inspired by their stories but more than anything it is inspired by their spirit — that elastic rubber-like ability man has to adapt and to weather the storm.”
Oh My Sweet Land runs one hour followed by a 30-minute food sharing and community conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Enemies: Lively Scenes of Love and Combat</title>
      <link>/productions/our-enemies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/our-enemies/</guid>
      <description>Reviews HIGHEST RATING!
&amp;#8220;Smart, daring and well constructed&amp;#8230; For a play about ideas, the kind of urgent ideas that don’t make it to American stages often enough, its debaters are just as complex and fleshed out as the ideas themselves.&amp;#8221; —San Francisco Chronicle (read full review)
&amp;#8220;Powerful, unforgettable theatre&amp;#8230; There’s sex, deep rumination, harsh conflict, galvanizing anger, violence, manipulation, lying, fierce intelligence, incisive criticism and genuine affection. Director Torange Yeghiazarian and her tremendous actors throw the conversation wide open and invite the audience to be active participants in the drama.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Dangerous Highway in the World</title>
      <link>/productions/most-dangerous-highway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/productions/most-dangerous-highway/</guid>
      <description>Reviews &amp;#8220;Poignant, poetic, and chilling&amp;#8230; A strong addition to Golden Thread’s repertory of new work about the Middle East.&amp;#8221; —San Francisco Examiner &amp;#8220;A superb performance from young Kiran Patel, who carries the entire drama with his exuberance and his deeply felt connection with Traffic.&amp;#8221; —Theater Dogs &amp;#8220;A lean, fast-moving narrative well delivered by a strong ensemble.&amp;#8221; —San Mateo Daily News &amp;#8220;Golden Thread Productions continues to bring us wonderful new stories and push theatre in a more diverse and inclusive direction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>